[music]
People share varying statistics regarding
employment rates for people who are deaf.
It ranges from 50% to 75%.
But what is the actual employment rate?
The actual employment rate may
not apply to all deaf people.
For example, women, people of color,
and those with additional disabilities
may have a different experience.
&gt;&gt; A welder.
&gt;&gt; A teacher.
&gt;&gt; Filmmaker.
&gt;&gt; Personal Trainer.
&gt;&gt; A yoga instructor
&gt;&gt; Dentist.
&gt;&gt; Mechanic.
&gt;&gt; Teaching for the Deaf and Blind.
&gt;&gt; I'm a researcher.
&gt;&gt; I'm an advocate.
[TEXT: Let’s look at some national data.]
&gt;&gt; A University of Texas at Austin
research team analyzed a sample
collected from the US census bureau.
The sample considers only individuals
ages 21-65 or “working age”
to exclude those retired
and those still pursuing education.
Using this data they pinpointed
the actual unemployment rates
for hearing individual and
deaf individuals.
72% of Hearing individuals are
working whereas 48%
of deaf individuals are working.
Of those not working, the federal
government identified 2 categories.
The first is unemployment meaning
people who are actively searching
for a job and need assistance.
The second category is called
Not in Labor Force and are those
not interested in working meaning
they have maybe retired early,
be at home raising a family
or seeking additional education.
Recall that unemployment means
actively searching for work.
When considering the unemployment
rates for the entire country there is not
a large discrepancy between the
general US hearing population
and deaf individuals.
[TEXT 4.9% and 4.6%]
Now remember that the
Not in Labor force category
includes individuals that are
not in the job market or not
actively seeking work.
In this category, the numbers are
drastically different.
23% of hearing people
whereas 47% of those deaf.
There are 5 subcategories
to the Not In Labor Force
category. This includes
women, veterans,
Native Americans, African Americans,
and deaf disabled.
Some of these individuals may have been
unsuccessful in finding employment
or may have been unsatisfied with
their work opportunities.
These individuals have a variety of
experiences and reasons for not working.
&gt;&gt; It’s a big challenge and
quite frustrating.
A number of the barriers exist
because the general public think
Deaf Blind people aren’t
able to do things.
&gt;&gt; I would be under a lot of stress.
&gt;&gt; Everything needs to be instantaneous.
Communication needs to happen
on the fly.
&gt;&gt; They didn't know how best
to communicate.
For my employer and manager,
writing messages was a struggle,
so I quit.
&gt;&gt; When it comes to doing my last
minute things, with my disability
I can’t do last minute things.
&gt;&gt; They see that I’m Deaf and a girl,
they think I can’t do the job.
&gt;&gt; Employers don't want to pay
interpreting expenses
because they're costly.
&gt;&gt; Generally there's a lack of experience
working with deaf people.
There's fewer opportunities.
There's a common misconception
that deaf individuals earn less than
their hearing counterparts.
This actually isn’t true,
the average salary for both groups
working full time is $52,000.
Hearing females earn $.82 to every $1
that a hearing male earns.
And deaf females earn $.76 compared
to each $1 a deaf male earns.
Being Deaf with an additional Disability
I face more difficulties.
If one has a physical disability,
a visible disability, it frightens employers,
and leads them to not hire
that disabled person.
If one has an invisible disability,
that you can't see,
such as ADHD or the like,
the person with that type
of disability &amp; normally
doesn’t disclose that.
But, when it is found out and realized
the individual may need
accommodations,&amp; and that
can take more time.
For me it wasn't hard finding a job,
it was more that I couldn't keep the job.
It is hard finding a job,
it's no joke.
Deaf individuals have an employment
rate of 63% whereas individuals that
are deaf with additional disabilities
are employed at a rate of 32%
and earn less.
Across the U.S. there are discrepancies
in pay for people of color and this
is true for individuals
who are deaf as well.
For example, people who are Latino
work more that those who are white,
but they earn significantly less. misspellings
It’s important to understand that
employment experiences are not
the same for all &amp;individuals
who are deaf.
Each has their own identity,
experience and needs.
The community should address this
diversity through support
and collaboration.
We hope to see the development
of job training, the chance to apply
for jobs, greater job opportunities
for deaf people, the ability to
show our skills, and greater
communication access.
Those are key.